

# Manuel Vigo

My aim is to help organizations innovate through a user-centered approach. I focus on driving innovation through design research, strategy, and rapid prototyping.

I value multidisciplinary and cross-cultural teams and have been fortunate to live and work on 4 continents.

- www.manuelvigo.com
- in linkedin.com/in/manuelvigo/
- +34 696 923 570

#### Languages:

English - Native Spanish - Native

### Nationalities:

Peru

**United States** 

# **Consulting Projects for:**

- •CERN (Switzerland)
- Konica Minolta (UK)
- •Ferrino (Italy)

#### **Hobbies:**

I play guitar and enjoy playing and recording music with friends. An avid reader, I enjoy literature and books on philosophy. Lately I've been brushing up on HTML and Arduino. A constant learner, curiosity is my biggest driver.

# Work Experience

# **CERN - The European Organization for Nuclear Research**

Sep 2017 - Oct 2017

# **Design and Innovation Intern**

- •Carried out user research, co-creation sessions, and rapid prototyping, to identify opportunities and execute projects to improve the interaction between the scientific community and innovators/entrepreneurs within CERN.
- •Hosted and facilitated Design Thinking and Collaborative Design workshops.

#### **Latin America For Less**

Jan 2017 - Present

# Special Projects Manager

- Managing SEO, and digital advertising strategy.
- •Advising on web development and UX projects.

Jun 2014 - Dec 2016

#### Marketing and UX Manager

- \*Built and led 9-person digital marketing, content, and web development teams.
- •Led design, user experience, SEO, and PPC advertising for all LAFL brands. Leading to conversion rate improvements of over 59% year-to-year.
- •Carried out design sprints to develop customized digital tools that improved user experience and efficiencies in the sales funnel.
- •Analyzed research and customer feedback to improve user-experience.
- •Managed building of new brand projects, and led the company's winning proposal for PeruDesignNet, a competition honoring innovative ideas.

Oct 2013 - Jun 2014

#### Marketing Manager

- •Oversaw digital marketing, advertising, website and content development.
- •Led complete redesign of websites, with a focus on mobile UX.
- •Developed and executed SEO strategy, A/B testing, and UX research

Jun 2013 - Sep 2014

## Content and Social Media Coordinator

•Developed and executed content strategy for internal blog, link outreach, and, social media.

#### **Next City**

Dec 2012 - Sep 2013

#### Journalist and Researcher

- •Researched and wrote a weekly article series on Lima's informal economy for The Rockefeller Foundation's Informal City Dialogues.
- •Part of Future Scenarios conferences in Lima, helping participants build a framework for understanding the next decades of Lima's growth.

#### **Peru This Week**

Apr 2011 - June 2013

#### News Editor

Over 700 articles written on business, economic, political, and cultural trends in Peru.

# Education

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

### IED Istituto Europeo di Design - Barcelona

Master in Design Management

Aug 2007 - Dec 2010

#### Florida International University

B.A in International Relations and Philosophy

1996 - 2005

#### Markham College

Graduated with honours. International Baccalaureate (IB) and IGCSE